<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Steph Locke</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/</link><description>Recent content on Steph Locke</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stephlocke.info/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Steph Locke</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/presenting/bio/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/presenting/bio/</guid><description>Tagline Data and AI technology expert for startups and enterprises
Bio Steph heads up a team of digital and app innovation architects in Microsoft, helping some of the UK&amp;rsquo;s biggest organisations use the cloud to deliver more value faster. She has a broad technology background in data, AI, and software and has experience running consultancies and startups. Steph loves open source, and the impact accessible tech can have on empowering people, so she dedicates her spare time to helping others improve their use of tech.</description></item><item><title>Working with Azure Functions</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/blog/working-with-azure-functions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/blog/working-with-azure-functions/</guid><description>This post is an overview of Azure Functions based on the session &amp;ldquo;Working with data using Azure Functions&amp;rdquo; that was first delivered at SQLBits with Liam Moat. See the slides for the session at Talks/Working with data using Azure Functions.
What are Azure Functions? Azure Functions are one of the latest abstractions away from needing to define everything yourself when performing activities using software.
First we abstracted away from the physical server to the virtual, then started using Platform as a Service (PaaS) or containerising code to run in the cloud.</description></item><item><title>Working with data using Azure Functions</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/presenting/talks/working_with_data_using_azure_functions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/presenting/talks/working_with_data_using_azure_functions/</guid><description>Session description Azure Functions are great for a wide range of scenarios, including working with data on a transactional or event-driven basis. In this session, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at how you can interact with Azure SQL, Cosmos DB, Event Hubs, and more so you can see how you can take a lightweight but code-first approach to building APIs, integrations, ETL, and maintenance routines.
Slides Presentation history March 18th 2023 @ SQLBits with Liam Moat</description></item><item><title>Building brilliant managers (including yourself!)</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/presenting/talks/build_brilliant_managers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/presenting/talks/build_brilliant_managers/</guid><description>Session description Too often, we chuck talented technologists into a promotion to the role of team lead or manager without any training or support. This can lead to a shaky foundation in their management style, many new managers quitting to go back to tech, and people being mis-handled as managers learn. In this session, I&amp;rsquo;ll take you through some of the concepts, frameworks, and support systems I think help a company grow great leaders.</description></item><item><title>Let’s banish "it works on my machine"</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/presenting/talks/works_on_my_machine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/presenting/talks/works_on_my_machine/</guid><description>Session description Between spending hours (or days!) making sure you can code and test locally and the difficulties of keeping remote environments up to date, sometimes we find ourselves falling back on &amp;ldquo;It works on my machine!&amp;rdquo;. Getting rid of the difficulties in making new development environments and maintaining testing infrastructure is really key to banishing the dreaded phrase. In this session, we&amp;rsquo;ll take you through some of the recent tools and techs that will not only make your life easier but will mean you never have to say &amp;ldquo;works on my machine&amp;rdquo; ever again.</description></item><item><title>Using GitHub Codespaces for Hugo development</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/blog/using-codespaces-for-hugo-development/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/blog/using-codespaces-for-hugo-development/</guid><description>In this blog post, I try using Github Codespaces to write this blog post about using Codespaces to write blog posts in Hugo! Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s meta 🤓
A GitHub Codespace is a cloud based developer environment attached to your GitHub repository. It contains the necessary dependencies to be able to work on your codebase in VS Code (in-browser or you can connect from your desktop!) and then commit your code. Having a Codespace means never having to get all those pesky project dependencies set up on your computer AND it means you&amp;rsquo;re always working from a clean environment so &amp;ldquo;Works on my machine&amp;rdquo; should be a thing of the past!</description></item><item><title>Developer Velocity</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/presenting/talks/developer_velocity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/presenting/talks/developer_velocity/</guid><description>Session description Join Steph and Chris as they run through Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s transformation from shipping boxed products to always-on online services. Developer Velocity is a critical part of that journey to ensure the teams can keep delivering value to their end-users at scale. In this session, you will learn about some of the tips &amp;amp; tricks that Microsoft used along the way.
Slides Video Presentation history May 4th 2022 @ Hybrid Virtual Group with Chris Reddington</description></item><item><title>The Microsoft Well Architected Framework for Data &amp; Analytics</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/presenting/talks/the_microsoft_well_architected_framework_data_analytics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/presenting/talks/the_microsoft_well_architected_framework_data_analytics/</guid><description>Session description With more than a decade of organisations running large data &amp;amp; analytics workloads in the cloud, Microsoft have extended their architecture framework to provide best practices and guidance for businesses. In this session, we’ll introduce the Well Architected Framework, go into detail about effective data architectures, and give you concrete next steps you can take whether you already have a cloud data architecture or are planning your first implementation.</description></item><item><title>Stop Teams being a noisy neighbour</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/blog/stop-teams-being-a-noisy-neighbour/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/blog/stop-teams-being-a-noisy-neighbour/</guid><description>You&amp;rsquo;ll hear about the noisy neighbour problem in tech, but did you know they meant Microsoft Teams? 😉 Teams as a collaboration tool has become increasingly important in a remote environment and many folks have talked about good meeting etiquette. What I&amp;rsquo;d like to do in this blog post, is cover some ways to make Teams easier day to day, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t generate lots of extra noise, anxiety, and context switching.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Solution Architect Manager</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/msft-csamgr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 09:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/msft-csamgr/</guid><description>Leading a team to foster Digital &amp;amp; Application Innovation at scale.</description></item><item><title>Joining Microsoft</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/blog/new-role-at-msft/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/blog/new-role-at-msft/</guid><description>Over the past five years I&amp;rsquo;ve been running my own consultancy and software companies. Last year was a period of reflection for both Nightingale HQ and myself. What do we want to be and where should we be spending our time? The answer for Nightingale HQ (NHQ) is a change towards more of a blended product and services offering in the manufacturing space. For me, it&amp;rsquo;s gaining a stronger foundation in technology leadership.</description></item><item><title>Chair</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/nightingalehq-chair/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 11:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/nightingalehq-chair/</guid><description>Chairing the Board to support Nightingale HQ&amp;rsquo;s growth plans.</description></item><item><title>Non-Executive Director</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/sqlsat-nonexec/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 11:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/sqlsat-nonexec/</guid><description>Supporting the setup of the new SQL Saturday not-for-profit.</description></item><item><title>CEO</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/lockedata-ceo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 12:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/lockedata-ceo/</guid><description>The founder of Locke Data, I help businesses build a data science capability.</description></item><item><title>CEO</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/nightingalehq-ceo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 12:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/nightingalehq-ceo/</guid><description>The co-founder of Nightingale HQ, I build solutions that support manufacturers in their digital transformation.</description></item><item><title>Community support</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/community/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/community/</guid><description>Hi!</description></item><item><title>Hello World!</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/blog/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/blog/hello-world/</guid><description>Hey hey! Welcome to the requisite first post in a new blog 👋
I endeavour to blog here when not related to a specific role etc.</description></item><item><title>Locke Data</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/otherblogs/itsalocke/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/otherblogs/itsalocke/</guid><description>Locke Data is a data science consultancy focussed on primarily on R and Azure. Read technical posts on the use of R and other tools.</description></item><item><title>Medium</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/otherblogs/medium/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/otherblogs/medium/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve used Medium over the years primarily for posts about the Microsoft Data Community and startup life.</description></item><item><title>Nightingale HQ</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/otherblogs/nhq/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/otherblogs/nhq/</guid><description>Nightingale HQ (NHQ) is a startup focused on improving productivity in the manufacturing sector through the use no-code programming, data, and AI.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://stephlocke.info/presenterpack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/presenterpack/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>