<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Developer Velocity on</title><link>/tags/developer-velocity/</link><description>Recent content in Developer Velocity on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/developer-velocity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Let’s banish "it works on my machine"</title><link>/presenting/talks/works_on_my_machine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/presenting/talks/works_on_my_machine/</guid><description>Session description Between spending hours (or days!) making sure you can code and test locally and the difficulties of keeping remote environments up to date, sometimes we find ourselves falling back on &amp;ldquo;It works on my machine!&amp;rdquo;. Getting rid of the difficulties in making new development environments and maintaining testing infrastructure is really key to banishing the dreaded phrase. In this session, we&amp;rsquo;ll take you through some of the recent tools and techs that will not only make your life easier but will mean you never have to say &amp;ldquo;works on my machine&amp;rdquo; ever again.</description></item><item><title>Using GitHub Codespaces for Hugo development</title><link>/blog/using-codespaces-for-hugo-development/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/using-codespaces-for-hugo-development/</guid><description>In this blog post, I try using Github Codespaces to write this blog post about using Codespaces to write blog posts in Hugo! Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s meta 🤓
A GitHub Codespace is a cloud based developer environment attached to your GitHub repository. It contains the necessary dependencies to be able to work on your codebase in VS Code (in-browser or you can connect from your desktop!) and then commit your code. Having a Codespace means never having to get all those pesky project dependencies set up on your computer AND it means you&amp;rsquo;re always working from a clean environment so &amp;ldquo;Works on my machine&amp;rdquo; should be a thing of the past!</description></item><item><title>Developer Velocity</title><link>/presenting/talks/developer_velocity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/presenting/talks/developer_velocity/</guid><description>Session description Join Steph and Chris as they run through Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s transformation from shipping boxed products to always-on online services. Developer Velocity is a critical part of that journey to ensure the teams can keep delivering value to their end-users at scale. In this session, you will learn about some of the tips &amp;amp; tricks that Microsoft used along the way.
Slides Video Presentation history May 4th 2022 @ Hybrid Virtual Group with Chris Reddington</description></item></channel></rss>