<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Steph Locke</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Steph Locke</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stephlocke.info/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Working with Azure Functions</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/blog/working-with-azure-functions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/blog/working-with-azure-functions/</guid><description>This post is an overview of Azure Functions based on the session &amp;ldquo;Working with data using Azure Functions&amp;rdquo; that was first delivered at SQLBits with Liam Moat. See the slides for the session at Talks/Working with data using Azure Functions.
What are Azure Functions? Azure Functions are one of the latest abstractions away from needing to define everything yourself when performing activities using software.
First we abstracted away from the physical server to the virtual, then started using Platform as a Service (PaaS) or containerising code to run in the cloud.</description></item><item><title>Using GitHub Codespaces for Hugo development</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/blog/using-codespaces-for-hugo-development/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/blog/using-codespaces-for-hugo-development/</guid><description>In this blog post, I try using Github Codespaces to write this blog post about using Codespaces to write blog posts in Hugo! Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s meta 🤓
A GitHub Codespace is a cloud based developer environment attached to your GitHub repository. It contains the necessary dependencies to be able to work on your codebase in VS Code (in-browser or you can connect from your desktop!) and then commit your code. Having a Codespace means never having to get all those pesky project dependencies set up on your computer AND it means you&amp;rsquo;re always working from a clean environment so &amp;ldquo;Works on my machine&amp;rdquo; should be a thing of the past!</description></item><item><title>Stop Teams being a noisy neighbour</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/blog/stop-teams-being-a-noisy-neighbour/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/blog/stop-teams-being-a-noisy-neighbour/</guid><description>You&amp;rsquo;ll hear about the noisy neighbour problem in tech, but did you know they meant Microsoft Teams? 😉 Teams as a collaboration tool has become increasingly important in a remote environment and many folks have talked about good meeting etiquette. What I&amp;rsquo;d like to do in this blog post, is cover some ways to make Teams easier day to day, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t generate lots of extra noise, anxiety, and context switching.</description></item><item><title>Joining Microsoft</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/blog/new-role-at-msft/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/blog/new-role-at-msft/</guid><description>Over the past five years I&amp;rsquo;ve been running my own consultancy and software companies. Last year was a period of reflection for both Nightingale HQ and myself. What do we want to be and where should we be spending our time? The answer for Nightingale HQ (NHQ) is a change towards more of a blended product and services offering in the manufacturing space. For me, it&amp;rsquo;s gaining a stronger foundation in technology leadership.</description></item><item><title>Hello World!</title><link>https://stephlocke.info/blog/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stephlocke.info/blog/hello-world/</guid><description>Hey hey! Welcome to the requisite first post in a new blog 👋
I endeavour to blog here when not related to a specific role etc.</description></item></channel></rss>